

Josey Dies

Academic Success Coach II



Professional Summary

Dedicated and adaptable Academic Success Coach with 2.5 years of experience in higher education. Highly skilled in counseling, communication, and relationship building with students and professionals for excellent success outcomes. Exceptional writing skills. Comfort in interpreting data and trends as related to student retention. Interested in the learning management systems and technology side of education and healthcare.



Work History

2018-07 -Current

Academic Success Coach II

Orbis Education, Indianapolis, IN

- Coach and advise a pipeline of students through program progression
- Build professional relationships and collaboration with partner faculty to increase student success
- Mentor and support growth of new success coaches
- Assess data and trends to maintain student retention
- Participate in projects and committees to improve processes
- Excellent organization in recording student interactions in a customer relationship management system

2015-08 -2019-08

Mental Health Counselor

Meridian Health Services, Muncie, IN

- Assessed acute psychiatric crises in the hospital emergency department
- Collaborated with psychiatrists, hospital physicians, and hospital social workers to implement an effective disposition for acute psychiatric crises
- Provided individual counseling clients with presenting issues such as depressive disorders, substance use disorders, anxiety disorders, anger issues, personality



Address

Indianapolis, IN, 46219

Phone

(260) 750-0499

E-mail

josey.dies@gmail.com



Excellent oral and written communication

Curriculum requirements expertise

Higher education practices knowledge

Mediation and crisis intervention

Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion training

disorders, relational concerns, homelessness, and trauma symptoms



Education

2013-08 -2015-05 Master of Arts: Clinical Mental Health Counseling

Ball State University - Muncie, IN

• Graduated with 3.88 GPA

2009-08 -2013-05 Bachelor of Arts: Psychology

Anderson University - Anderson, IN

 Graduated with 3.84 GPA, Magna Cum Laude with Psychology Honors



Interests

Growth & integration of diversity, equity, and inclusion in higher education and the workplace